Austin Gathii

Software Engineer

🗣 Nairobi, Kenya 🗷 gathiiaustin@gmail.com 📞 +254 716611612 🕻 Github 🛅 LinkedIn

Personal Website

PROFILE

I am a software engineer currently working as a front-end developer, specializing in React and TypeScript. My primary passion is machine learning and associated technologies which I have expressed through python-based personal projects.

I am passionate about the future of computer technology and I enjoy working in organizations where I can meaningfully contribute to that future.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer

Leta.ai ♂

Nairobi, Kenya

- Developed, maintained, and managed a comprehensive logistics management platform utilizing React and TypeScript.
- Integrated backend services via gRPC and implemented new features
- · Optimized performance and resolved bugs to enhance system efficiency and user experience.

Web Developer Sep 2022 - May 2023 Nairobi, Kenya

Standard Media Group PLC 🛮

- Maintained and debugged large API codebases built in Laravel
- Managed media websites with medium to high levels of user traffic using Laravel and Vue.js
- Rebuilt an obsolete event ticketing website in Laravel

Data Analyst Mar 2022 - Aug 2022 Nairobi, Kenya

Microhouse Technologies

- Managed, cleaned and maintained a large SQL database of user data in a team with 2 other engineers
- Analyzed said database to extract and derive trends and predictive data and used the matplotlib library in Python to visualize it.

Web Developer Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Smart Data Analytical Limited

- Developed a travel blogging site for a client based on Wordpress and created custom PHP plugins to fulfill more specific client requirements.
- Designed basic graphics and illustrations for an institution's website using Adobe Illustrator.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Informatics and Computer Science

Strathmore University

2018 - 2022 Nairobi, Kenya

Earned a bachelor's degree in Computer Science over the course of 4 years that included courses on the fundamentals of computer technology as well as several specializations in the field such as mobile development, web development and database management.

gathiiaustin@gmail.com 1/2

May 2023 - present

Nairobi, Kenya

PROJECTS

Arbora 🗗

Jun 2024 - Aug 2024

- Developed Arbora, an Al-powered study webapp using the Gemini API to generate flashcards and questions from users' notes, continuously assessing understanding through interactions.
- Implemented an intuitive UI representing documents as trees, with foliage color indicating knowledge retention, allowing users to easily track their learning progress.

VoteTallyKE □

Aug 2022 - Sep 2022

- I built a computer vision system for locating and recognizing handwritten digits on scanned forms then tallying the figures with 95% accuracy.
- The input dataset was the publicly available polling station forms for the recently concluded 2022 Kenyan General Elections

Personal Website 🛮

May 2022 - Jul 2022

- I created fully responsive Javascript-based developer portfolio website built on the React framework with SCSS for styling.
- The website is highly customizable which also allows it to serve as a template for other developers.

Attendance Tracking System 2

Jul 2021 – Feb 2022

- I built a python based computer vision and machine learning system that performs facial tracking and recognition for my final year university project.
- It integrates with a camera and touchpad to provide attendance tracking of personnel within an organization or enclosed area with specific entry points

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Front End

Python, Typescript, Javascript, PHP

React, SCSS, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Databases

Back End

SQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Laravel, FastAPI

2/2 gathiiaustin@gmail.com